<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hugo on Shariq Jamil | dev-blog</title>
    <link>https://shariq1989.github.io/tags/hugo/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hugo on Shariq Jamil | dev-blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://shariq1989.github.io/tags/hugo/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Smarter image optimization</title>
      <link>https://shariq1989.github.io/posts/find_move/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shariq1989.github.io/posts/find_move/</guid>
      <description>This blog has been a nice source of motivation to continue improving my code and development processes. In my previous post, I discussed the process of writing a Bash script to resize and optimize images for publishing to our family&amp;rsquo;s recipe blog. I mentioned that one improvement I could make is to automate the process of identifying which files needed to be resized.
The original script I place large images into the &amp;ldquo;optimize&amp;rdquo; directory which are then backed up and processed when I run the following script.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing Images for the Web</title>
      <link>https://shariq1989.github.io/posts/optimizing_images/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shariq1989.github.io/posts/optimizing_images/</guid>
      <description>When we first started adding photos of food to JamilGhar, we did not think about image size. The average image we posted to the blog was between 2 and 8 megabytes and the resolution was over 3000 x 3000 pixels. The image below is an example.
 For most blogs, images should be less than 1000 pixels in the longest direction and preferably less than 100 kB. Featured or &amp;ldquo;hero&amp;rdquo; images can be up to 500 kB if used sparingly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating blog posts in Hugo</title>
      <link>https://shariq1989.github.io/posts/adding_content/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shariq1989.github.io/posts/adding_content/</guid>
      <description>Adding or updating posts in Hugo is easy. After all, content management is one of the framework&amp;rsquo;s primary features. My wife has little interest in understanding the software development side of blogging. Even she finds it effortless to add blog posts in markdown and half-a-dozen images per post through Github.
Directory structure In Hugo, posts go into the content folder which will be in the root directory of your site. Some theme&amp;rsquo;s may have varying patterns.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adding a theme in Hugo</title>
      <link>https://shariq1989.github.io/posts/setting_up_hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shariq1989.github.io/posts/setting_up_hugo/</guid>
      <description>Create a Hugo site After installing Hugo, I was ready to start on the blog. I have a directory (or &amp;ldquo;folder&amp;rdquo; for Windows folks) on my laptop for software development projects. Most of these projects are also hosted in my Github account.
I navigated to that directory and created a folder called food-blog. Inside food-blog, I ran Hugo&amp;rsquo;s command to start a new site.
hugo new site food-blog  In the screenshot below, you can see that the new Hugo site was created successfully.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing Hugo in Linux (Ubuntu)</title>
      <link>https://shariq1989.github.io/posts/installing_hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shariq1989.github.io/posts/installing_hugo/</guid>
      <description>To begin working on the blog, I needed to install Hugo first. My laptop runs Pop_OS!, a Linux distribution based on Ubuntu. There are quite a few ways to install Hugo and I chose to install the official package using apt-get.
sudo apt-get install hugo  Once the install was complete, I verified the install
hugo version  As shown in the screenshot below, Hugo version 0.74.3 installed successfully on my machine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We need a blog stack</title>
      <link>https://shariq1989.github.io/posts/intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shariq1989.github.io/posts/intro/</guid>
      <description>Problem My wife and I have always wanted to work on an online project together. She is creative, and I can figure out technology. A multitude of reasons pushed us to start a blog in early 2021.
 My hunger for a software-dev-related side project A desire to digitalize our growing three-ring recipe binder Repeated requests for the same recipes (mostly Thai Red Curry and Butter Chicken) from friends and family  It was easy to devise requirements as we thought through different features (blog setup, adding posts and pictures, monetization, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>