<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Linux on Shariq Jamil | dev-blog</title>
    <link>https://shariq1989.github.io/tags/linux/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Linux on Shariq Jamil | dev-blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://shariq1989.github.io/tags/linux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Refactoring/Find-&amp;-Replace on a WordPress site</title>
      <link>https://shariq1989.github.io/posts/mass_updates_wordpress_site/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shariq1989.github.io/posts/mass_updates_wordpress_site/</guid>
      <description>I help my dad maintain a WordPress site for his business. He recently opened a new location and needed a new WordPress site created for it. The only differences between the two sites are the branch name (ex. &amp;lsquo;Los Angeles&amp;rsquo; instead of &amp;lsquo;San Diego&amp;rsquo;) and phone number (&amp;lsquo;111-222-3333&amp;rsquo; instead of &amp;lsquo;222-333-4444&amp;rsquo;).
 The site is not stored in version control so downloading the source code, using an IDE to run find/replace and pushing updates wasn&amp;rsquo;t a straight-forward option.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Erasing personal data from hard drives or solid-state drives</title>
      <link>https://shariq1989.github.io/posts/wiping_disks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shariq1989.github.io/posts/wiping_disks/</guid>
      <description>Over the years I have ended up with roughly a half dozen computers in various stages of decay. Two water-damaged Macbooks. An old HP laptop my dad handed down to me to &amp;ldquo;make faster and find a home for&amp;rdquo;. A gaming desktop from college that was caked in dust and shorted when powered up ten years later. One task I had to perform for all these machines was to collect and remove any personal data from internal storage (hard drives/solid-state drives).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing Hugo in Linux (Ubuntu)</title>
      <link>https://shariq1989.github.io/posts/installing_hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shariq1989.github.io/posts/installing_hugo/</guid>
      <description>To begin working on the blog, I needed to install Hugo first. My laptop runs Pop_OS!, a Linux distribution based on Ubuntu. There are quite a few ways to install Hugo and I chose to install the official package using apt-get.
sudo apt-get install hugo  Once the install was complete, I verified the install
hugo version  As shown in the screenshot below, Hugo version 0.74.3 installed successfully on my machine.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
