<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Shariq Jamil | dev-blog</title>
    <link>https://shariq1989.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Shariq Jamil | dev-blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://shariq1989.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Adding a theme in Hugo</title>
      <link>https://shariq1989.github.io/posts/setting_up_hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shariq1989.github.io/posts/setting_up_hugo/</guid>
      <description>Create a Hugo site After installing Hugo, I was ready to start on the blog. I have a directory (or &amp;ldquo;folder&amp;rdquo; for Windows folks) on my laptop for software development projects. Most of these projects are also hosted in my Github account.
I navigated to that directory and created a folder called food-blog. Inside food-blog, I ran Hugo&amp;rsquo;s command to start a new site.
hugo new site food-blog  In the screenshot below, you can see that the new Hugo site was created successfully.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing Hugo in Linux (Ubuntu)</title>
      <link>https://shariq1989.github.io/posts/installing_hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shariq1989.github.io/posts/installing_hugo/</guid>
      <description>To begin working on the blog, I needed to install Hugo first. My laptop runs Pop_OS!, a Linux distribution based on Ubuntu. There are quite a few ways to install Hugo and I chose to install the official package using apt-get.
sudo apt-get install hugo  Once the install was complete, I verified the install
hugo version  As shown in the screenshot below, Hugo version 0.74.3 installed successfully on my machine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We need a blog stack</title>
      <link>https://shariq1989.github.io/posts/intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shariq1989.github.io/posts/intro/</guid>
      <description>Problem My wife and I have always wanted to work on an online project together. She is creative, and I can figure out technology. A multitude of reasons pushed us to start a blog in early 2021.
 My hunger for a software-dev-related side project A desire to digitalize our growing three-ring recipe binder Repeated requests for the same recipes (mostly Thai Red Curry and Butter Chicken) from friends and family  It was easy to devise requirements as we thought through different features (blog setup, adding posts and pictures, monetization, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>